[
  {
    "id": "a0001",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which fuel system does aerobic system use?",
    "correctAnswer": "Glycogen, fats, protein",
    "optionValues": [
      "Creatine from glucose supplies",
      "Glycogen only",
      "Glycogen, fats, protein",
      "Citric acid"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0002",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The sport of shot put relies primarily on which energy system?",
    "correctAnswer": "ATP-CP",
    "optionValues": [
      "Anaerobic",
      "ATP-CP",
      "Aerobic",
      "Lactic acid"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0003",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "A high aerobic capacity (cardio-respiratory endurance) is most important for?",
    "correctAnswer": "Removal of lactic acid",
    "optionValues": [
      "Increased muscle strength",
      "Removal of lactic acid",
      "Improved flexibility",
      "Preventing muscle breakdown"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0004",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "What by-product does ATP-CP produce?",
    "correctAnswer": "None of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Creatine Phosphate",
      "Water",
      "Adenosine Triphophate",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0005",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "What fitness component matches the aerobic energy system?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cardio-respiratory endurance",
    "optionValues": [
      "Speed",
      "Agility",
      "Cardio-respiratory endurance",
      "Muscle endurance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0006",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following amino acids cannot provide a substrate for gluconeogenesis?",
    "correctAnswer": "leucine",
    "optionValues": [
      "leucine",
      "tryptophan",
      "histidine",
      "isoleucine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0007",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "How much dietary protein should endurance athletes consume daily?",
    "correctAnswer": "1.2-1.7g per kg body weight per day",
    "optionValues": [
      "<0.8 g per kg body weight per day",
      "0.8-1.2 g per kg body weight per day",
      "1.2-1.7g per kg body weight per day",
      ">2.0g per kg body weight per day"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0008",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "What is the ideal carbohydrate recommendation during training for a well-trained endurance athlete competing at high intensity (for more than 2.5 hours)?",
    "correctAnswer": "90g glucose plus fructose per hour",
    "optionValues": [
      "60g glucose plus fructose per hour",
      "90g glucose per hour",
      "90g glucose plus fructose per hour",
      "60g glucose per hour"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0009",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "What is the basic functional unit of skeletal muscle tisue?",
    "correctAnswer": "the sarcomere",
    "optionValues": [
      "the muscle fibre",
      "the sarcomere",
      "the myofibril",
      "the sarcoplasmic reticulum"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0010",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "During marathon running, maximum amount of energy is derived from:",
    "correctAnswer": "Fat",
    "optionValues": [
      "Glucose",
      "Amino acids",
      "Fat",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0011",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The energy system that initially functions during weight lifting is:",
    "correctAnswer": "Phosphagen system",
    "optionValues": [
      "B-Oxidation",
      "TCA",
      "Glycolysis",
      "Phosphagen system"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0012",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The Lactic acid pathway supplies energy for:",
    "correctAnswer": "upto 10 seconds",
    "optionValues": [
      "upto 30 seconds",
      "upto 20 seconds",
      "upto 10 seconds",
      "upto 60 seconds"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0013",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The strategy that helps management of lactic acidosis is",
    "correctAnswer": "Bicarbonate loading",
    "optionValues": [
      "Protein loading",
      "Bicarbonate loading",
      "Glycogen Loading",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0014",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "One NADH+ molecule produces:",
    "correctAnswer": "3 ATP",
    "optionValues": [
      "3 ATP",
      "6 ATP",
      "12 ATP",
      "36 ATP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0015",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Electron transport system occurs in:",
    "correctAnswer": "Mitochondria",
    "optionValues": [
      "Cytoplasm",
      "Endoplasmic Reticulum",
      "Mitochondria",
      "Nucleus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0016",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The total amount of energy produced when one molecule of glucose is completely oxidised:",
    "correctAnswer": "38 ATP",
    "optionValues": [
      "12 ATP",
      "32 ATP",
      "34 ATP",
      "38 ATP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0017",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which one of the following is an essential amino acid?",
    "correctAnswer": "Isoleucine",
    "optionValues": [
      "Isoleucine",
      "Aspartic acid",
      "Fumaric acid",
      "Glutamic acid"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0018",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The optimum carbohydrate recommendation for an endurance athlete (training for 1-3 hours/day at moderate-to-high intensity) is:",
    "correctAnswer": "6 to 10gm/kg body weight",
    "optionValues": [
      "4 to 6gm/kg body weight",
      "6 to 8gm/kg body weight",
      "4 to 8gm/kg body weight",
      "6 to 10gm/kg body weight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0019",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Glycogen loading is recommended for endurance athletes performing activity at or above this duration:",
    "correctAnswer": "90 Minutes",
    "optionValues": [
      "30 Minutes",
      "45 Minutes",
      "60 Minutes",
      "90 Minutes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0020",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The ideal carbohydrate content in a pre-competition meal (taken 3-4 hours before event) is:",
    "correctAnswer": "150-200 grams",
    "optionValues": [
      "100-150 grams",
      "150-200 grams",
      "200-250 grams",
      "250-300 grams"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0021",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The carbohydrate recommendation for an athlete performing moderate-to-high intensity endurance exercise (lasting longer than 1 hour) is:",
    "correctAnswer": "60 grams per hour",
    "optionValues": [
      "50 grams per hour",
      "60 grams per hour",
      "70 grams per hour",
      "80 grams per hour"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0022",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Protein requirements of male athletes are higher than those of female athletes by:",
    "correctAnswer": "25%",
    "optionValues": [
      "10%",
      "15%",
      "20%",
      "25%"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0023",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "One of the following is a marker of muscle protein degradation:",
    "correctAnswer": "3-Methyl Histidine",
    "optionValues": [
      "Glutamine",
      "Uric acid",
      "3-Methyl Histidine",
      "3-Methyl valine "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0024",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Post game meal must contain:",
    "correctAnswer": "75 grams carbohydrate & 25 grams of protein",
    "optionValues": [
      "75 grams carbohydrate & 25 grams of protein",
      "65 grams carbohydrate & 15 grams of protein",
      "55 grams carbohydrate & 12 grams of protein",
      "45 grams carbohydrate & 10 grams of protein"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0025",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "During absorption from the intestine, Fructose uses which of the following transporters?",
    "correctAnswer": "GLUT-5",
    "optionValues": [
      "GLUT-1",
      "GLUT-2",
      "GLUT-4",
      "GLUT-5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0026",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The International Olympic Committee  guidelines for consumption of carbohydrate during exercise are between:",
    "correctAnswer": "20 to 60 gm per hour",
    "optionValues": [
      "20 to 60 gm per hour",
      "20 to 40 mg per hour",
      "20 to 40 gm per hour",
      "20 to 60 mg per hour"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0027",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "As per NIN, the recommended amount of protein for strength athletes is:",
    "correctAnswer": "1.0-1.5 gm/kg body weight",
    "optionValues": [
      "0.8-1.0 gm/kg body weight",
      "1.0-1.5 gm/kg body weight",
      "2-2.5 gm/kg body weight",
      "3-3.5 gm/kg body weight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0028",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "The antioxidant effect of Alpha lipoic acid is because it:",
    "correctAnswer": "Increases glutathione levels",
    "optionValues": [
      "Is a part of SOD enzyme complex",
      "Is a part of glutathione peroxidase system",
      "Increases glutathione levels",
      "Scavenges peroxyl radicals"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0029",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Isotonic and hypotonic dehydration is common amongst which athletes?",
    "correctAnswer": "boxers, wrestlers and gymnasts",
    "optionValues": [
      "marathon runners",
      "boxers, wrestlers and gymnasts",
      "football players",
      "not common in any sport"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0030",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Which of the following terms refer to breakdown of muscle fibers that occurs after strenuous exercise?",
    "correctAnswer": "rhabdomyolysis",
    "optionValues": [
      "hemolysis",
      "fibrinolysis",
      "autolysis",
      "rhabdomyolysis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0031",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Chromium supplementation claims to:",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "improve body composition",
      "increase lean body mass",
      " lower fat mass",
      "All of the above "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0032",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Exercise mobilises and redistributes magnesium to meet metabolic needs and it is lost in sweat, feces and urine.",
    "correctAnswer": "TRUE",
    "optionValues": [
      "TRUE",
      "FALSE"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0033",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "When iron stores are depleted- the synthesis of red blood cells is impaired, cell size is reduced and the color becomes pale resulting in:",
    "correctAnswer": "Microcytic hypochromic anemia",
    "optionValues": [
      "Aplastic anemia",
      "Microcytic hypochromic anemia",
      "Hemolytic anemia",
      "Sickle cell anemia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0034",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Athletes in weight-category sports (e.g. gymnasts, figure skaters, boxers) and endurance athletes have a high risk of:",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Eating disorders",
      "Low BMD",
      "Menstrual dysfunction",
      "All of the above "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0035",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "To prevent deficieny, athletes must maintain their serum 25-hydroxy Vitamin D at a minimum level of:",
    "correctAnswer": "30ng per ml",
    "optionValues": [
      "35ng per ml",
      "30ng per ml",
      "20ng per ml",
      "15ng per ml "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0036",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Vitamin E is involved in oxidative metabolism of which type of muscle fibres?",
    "correctAnswer": "Option1 and 3",
    "optionValues": [
      "Type 1 (red slow twitch)",
      "Type 2a (pink fast twitch)",
      "Type 2b (white fast twitch)",
      "Option1 and 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0037",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Athletes on low calorie diet and endurance athletes on high carbohydrate diet are prone to:",
    "correctAnswer": "Zinc deficiency",
    "optionValues": [
      "Selenium deficiency",
      "Zinc deficiency",
      "Vitamin A deficiency",
      "Magnesium deficiency "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0038",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "At what stage of exercise, should you aim to be well hydrated?",
    "correctAnswer": "Before beginning exercise",
    "optionValues": [
      "Halfway through exercise",
      "After you have finished exercising",
      "Before beginning exercise",
      "A few hours after exercising"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0039",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Dietary sources of antioxidants include:",
    "correctAnswer": "Vitamins E, C and A",
    "optionValues": [
      "Vitamin B6, Iron and Calcium",
      "Vitamin D, E and B",
      "Vitamin B12, Iron and Vitamin C",
      "Vitamins E, C and A"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0040",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Deficiency of which of the following minerals may cause muscle cramps in athletes?",
    "correctAnswer": "Magnesium",
    "optionValues": [
      "Chromium",
      "Selenium",
      "Magnesium",
      "Iron"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0041",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "1",
    "question": "Antioxidants are important to fight \"free radicals\"because they:",
    "correctAnswer": "damage cells",
    "optionValues": [
      "damage cells",
      "Increase need of calorie supplying nutrients",
      "destroy stored glucose",
      "limit conversion of protein to ATP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0042",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "During exercise, which of the following nutrients is lost in highest amount?",
    "correctAnswer": "Water",
    "optionValues": [
      "Fats",
      "Electrolytes",
      "Carbohydrates",
      "Water"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0043",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Which of the following is not a function of water?",
    "correctAnswer": "Acts as a fuel",
    "optionValues": [
      "Coolant",
      "Acts as a fuel",
      "Transports nutrients",
      "Acid-Base balance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0044",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Moderate-intensity exercise can raise body temperature by ________ degree every 5 min",
    "correctAnswer": "1",
    "optionValues": [
      "5",
      "2",
      "1",
      "1.5"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0045",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Cardiac re-distribution involves",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Increased blood flow to the skin",
      "Re-distribution of cardiac output from muscle to periphery",
      "Heat loss from skin to environment from convection & radiation",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0046",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Which of the following is not heat-related?",
    "correctAnswer": "DOMS",
    "optionValues": [
      "Heat stroke",
      "Muscle cramps",
      "Heat exhaustion",
      "DOMS"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0047",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "The key re-hydration strategy is to replace ___litre of fluids per kg loss of body weight",
    "correctAnswer": "1-1.5",
    "optionValues": [
      "2.5-3",
      "2-2.5",
      "1-1.5",
      "0.5-1"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0048",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Hyperhydration has been suggested to enhance performance only during hot & humid environmental conditions",
    "correctAnswer": "This statement is true",
    "optionValues": [
      "This statement is true",
      "This statement is false",
      "This statement is partly true",
      "Inconclusive research"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0049",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "The amount of sodium required  for optimal fluid absorption & prevention of hyponatremia is",
    "correctAnswer": "10-30mmol/L",
    "optionValues": [
      "40-50 mmol/L",
      "50-60 mmol/L",
      "5-10 mmol/L",
      "10-30mmol/L"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0050",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Gastro-intestinal problems during long distance endurance runs are due to the ingestion of",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "protein solutions",
      "concentrated carbohydrated solutions",
      "high osmolality solutions",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0051",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Seizures, coma and death can occur in which of the following",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "severe dehydration",
      "hyponatremia",
      "heat stroke",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0052",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "How many grams of carbohydrates per kg body weight should athletes ingest 1 to 4 hours before aerobic endurance exercise or competition?",
    "correctAnswer": "1 to 4 g",
    "optionValues": [
      "6 g",
      "8 to 10 g",
      "1 to 4 g",
      "6 to 8 g"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0053",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Ingestion of large amounts of which monosaccharide is not recommended during exercise due to the greater likelihood of gastroinstestinal problems?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fructose",
    "optionValues": [
      "Glucose",
      "Fructose",
      "Sucrose",
      "Maltodextrin"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0054",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "The preferred Carbohydrate-to-Protein ratio in a post-training meal is:",
    "correctAnswer": "4:01",
    "optionValues": [
      "2:01",
      "3:02",
      "3:04",
      "4:01"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0055",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Post exercise carbohydrate and protein consumption should occur within ____ minutes for optimal replenishment of glycogen stores and muscle repair",
    "correctAnswer": "30 minutes",
    "optionValues": [
      "30 minutes",
      "90 minutes",
      "50 minutes",
      "5 minutes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0056",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Which of the following can be consumed during a full marathon?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Sports drink",
      "Carbohydrate gel",
      "Banana",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0057",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "During exercise, athletes should consume a carbohydrate–electrolyte solution that delivers ________ carbohydrate solution every 15 to 20 minutes to sustain blood glucose levels.",
    "correctAnswer": "6% to 8%",
    "optionValues": [
      "8% to 10%",
      "4% to 6%",
      "6% to 8%",
      "10% to 12%"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0058",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "During exercise of 1-1.5 hour duration, the carbohydrate intake must be ____ to ____ g per hour:",
    "correctAnswer": "30 to 60 g",
    "optionValues": [
      "30 to 60 g",
      "50 to 70 g",
      "40 to 50 g",
      "60 to 70 g "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0059",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "Classic method of Carbohydrate loading is generally started ______ before the competition day",
    "correctAnswer": "7 days",
    "optionValues": [
      "10 days",
      "7 days",
      "15 days",
      "9 days"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0060",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "1 gram glycogen requires ______ grams of water for storage",
    "correctAnswer": "3",
    "optionValues": [
      "2",
      "1",
      "3",
      "4"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0061",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "2",
    "question": "When glycogen is depleted, which enzyme is elevated in the blood?",
    "correctAnswer": "glycogen synthetase",
    "optionValues": [
      "glycogen synthetase",
      "glycogen phosphorylase",
      "glucosidase",
      "glucosyltransferase"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0062",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "Which of the following sports is not included in the power event category?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cricket",
    "optionValues": [
      "Weightlifting",
      "Gymnastics",
      "Shot Put",
      "Cricket"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0063",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "Power development is dependent on the following muscle fibre type",
    "correctAnswer": "Both Type IIa & Type IIb",
    "optionValues": [
      "Type IIa",
      "Type IIb",
      "Both Type IIa & Type IIb",
      "Type I"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0064",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "Power events majorily rely on the following energy system",
    "correctAnswer": "Both Option1 and 2",
    "optionValues": [
      "ATP-CP",
      "Anaerobic glycolysis",
      "Oxidative phosphorylation",
      "Both Option1 and 2"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0065",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "In which of the following sports, do athletes undergo repetitive patterns of weight gain and weight loss to build muscle and then reduce body-fat levels?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bodybuilding",
    "optionValues": [
      "Sprinting",
      "Swimming",
      "Bodybuilding",
      "Gymnastics"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0066",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "To attain weight loss in wrestlers, the daily calorie intake from the macronutrients (Carbohydrates/Proteins/Fats) can be:",
    "correctAnswer": "55/20/25",
    "optionValues": [
      "70/10/20",
      "60/20/20",
      "55/20/25",
      "65/15/20"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0067",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "On competition day, weightlifters highly rely on _________ for energy",
    "correctAnswer": "Phosphocreatine",
    "optionValues": [
      "Fats",
      "Phosphocreatine",
      "Amino acids",
      "Carbohydrates"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0068",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "During multiple bouts of high intensity activity in competition, athletes need to consume beverage containing carbohydrates and ____________",
    "correctAnswer": "Electrolytes",
    "optionValues": [
      "Proteins",
      "Fats",
      "Electrolytes",
      "Iron"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0069",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "To make weight in the last few days before competition, athletes commonly attempt to lose weight rapidly by a combination of:",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Sweating",
      "Severe restriction of food",
      "Drastic drop in fluid intake",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0070",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "A high body mass is an advantage in which of the following sports?",
    "correctAnswer": "Throwing events",
    "optionValues": [
      "Gymnastics",
      "Figure skating",
      "Swimming",
      "Throwing events"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0071",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "During Endurance events of more than 2.5hrs duration, carbohydrate intake must be upto ______",
    "correctAnswer": "90 gm/hr",
    "optionValues": [
      "50 gm/hr",
      "55 gm/hr",
      "65 gm/hr",
      "90 gm/hr"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0072",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "Carbohydrate mouth rinsing is one of the ways to ____________________",
    "correctAnswer": "Stimulate taste receptor cells",
    "optionValues": [
      "Boost protein synthesis",
      "Increase strength",
      "Stimulate taste receptor cells",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0073",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "It is beneficial for an endurance athlete to take ______ caffeine (along with carbohydrates) 30mins before an event",
    "correctAnswer": "3-6mg/kg",
    "optionValues": [
      ">6gm/kg",
      "3-6mg/kg",
      ">6mg/kg",
      "3-6gm/kg"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0074",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "Which diet is most suitable for endurance athletes?",
    "correctAnswer": "High Carbohydrate, Moderate Protein diet",
    "optionValues": [
      "High Carbohydrate, Moderate Protein diet",
      "Low Carbohydrate, Moderate Protein diet",
      "Low Carbohydrate, High Protein diet",
      "Low Carbohydrate, Low Protein diet"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0075",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "As the duration of a tennis match increases, _____________ becomes important for energy provision.",
    "correctAnswer": "Fat Oxidation",
    "optionValues": [
      "Glycogen utilisation",
      "Protein Oxidation",
      "Fat Oxidation",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0076",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "Racket Sports rely on:",
    "correctAnswer": "Both Aerobic & Anaerobic energy systems",
    "optionValues": [
      "Only Phosphagen energy system",
      "Only Aerobic energy system",
      "Only Anaerobic energy system",
      "Both Aerobic & Anaerobic energy systems"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0077",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "The fat recommendation during the \"specific training phase\"for a racket sport is",
    "correctAnswer": "1-1.5g/kg body weight",
    "optionValues": [
      "1-1.5g/kg body weight",
      "1.5-2g/kg body weight",
      "0.8-1g/kg body weight",
      "2-2.5g/kg body weight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0078",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "Which of the following sport is played with a racket and a shuttle?",
    "correctAnswer": "Badminton",
    "optionValues": [
      "Squash",
      "Tennis",
      "Badminton",
      "Table Tennis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0079",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "Which of the following external factors will influence the athlete's performance in racket sports?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Surface of the court",
      "Equipment used",
      "Environmental conditions",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0080",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "One of the benefits of using Multiple Transportable Carbs during Endurance Exercise is____________:",
    "correctAnswer": "Minimal gastrointestinal distress",
    "optionValues": [
      "Reduced carbohydrate oxidation",
      "Minimal gastrointestinal distress",
      "Decreased fluid delivery",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0081",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "During an ultra-endurance event, the athlete may benefit from intake of _________:",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Carbohydrates",
      "Electrolytes",
      "Sodium Bicarbonate",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0082",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "An endurance sport is characterised by __________:",
    "correctAnswer": "Low-to-moderate intensity, Long duration",
    "optionValues": [
      "Low-to-moderate intensity, Long duration",
      "High Intensity, long duration",
      "Low-to-moderate intensity, short duration",
      "High Intensity, short duration"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0083",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "Which of the following events is the longest in duration?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ironman",
    "optionValues": [
      "Full Marathon",
      "10km open water swimming",
      "Ironman",
      "Olympic Triathlon"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0084",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "What kind of body composition is ideal for an endurance athlete?",
    "correctAnswer": "Low Body weight with low body fat%",
    "optionValues": [
      "High Body weight with moderate body fat%",
      "Low Body weight with low body fat%",
      "Low Body weight with moderate body fat%",
      "Low Body weight with high body fat%"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0085",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "The minimum desirable body fat% in endurance athletes is ___________:",
    "correctAnswer": "Males - 8% and Females - 12%",
    "optionValues": [
      "Males - 8% and Females - 12%",
      "Males - 20% and Females - 15%",
      "Males - 15% and Females - 20%",
      "Males - 12% and Females - 8%"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0086",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "The primary energy system(s) used in team sports:",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "ATP-CP",
      "Aerobic",
      "Anaerobic glycolysis",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0087",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "___________ athletes cover on an average of 10-13 km during  football matches",
    "correctAnswer": "mid-field",
    "optionValues": [
      "forwards",
      "defenders",
      "mid-field",
      "goal keepers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0088",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "The correct dose of protein post training for cricketers is:",
    "correctAnswer": "20-25g",
    "optionValues": [
      "15-20g",
      "20-25g",
      "30g",
      "10g"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0089",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "Daily requirements of carbohydrates for recovery from moderate-to-heavy endurance training (pre-season) for football players is:",
    "correctAnswer": "7 -10 gm/kg body weight",
    "optionValues": [
      "7 -10 gm/kg body weight",
      "10-12 gm/kg body weight",
      "4 -5 gm/kg body weight",
      "6-8 gm/kg body weight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0090",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "The key vitamin essential for recovery from muscle soreness is:",
    "correctAnswer": "Vitamin C",
    "optionValues": [
      "Vitamin A",
      "Vitamin E",
      "Vitamin C",
      "Vitamin D"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0091",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "Micronutrient requirements during hockey are increased due to the following:",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Increased BMR",
      "Increased need for tissue maintenance & repair",
      "Increased concentrations of mitochondrial enzymes",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0092",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "What should be the carbohydrate quantity in a 3-hour pre-training low-glycemic meal for a basketball player?",
    "correctAnswer": "3 gm/kg body weight",
    "optionValues": [
      "1 gm/kg body weight",
      "2.5 gm/kg body weight",
      "3 gm/kg body weight",
      "4 gm/kg body weight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0093",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "Which of the following is a good meal option for half-time during a hockey match?",
    "correctAnswer": "Banana",
    "optionValues": [
      "BCAA",
      "Banana",
      "Chocolate bar",
      "plain water"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0094",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "Which of the following is the most beneficial supplement for kabaddi players?",
    "correctAnswer": "Creatine",
    "optionValues": [
      "Creatine",
      "Caffeine",
      "Multivitamin",
      "Beta-alanine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0095",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "3",
    "question": "The key recovery supplement for team sport athletes is:",
    "correctAnswer": "Glutamine",
    "optionValues": [
      "Multivitamin",
      "Glutamine",
      "Collagen",
      "Caffeine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0096",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "If a sportsperson fails a dope test- who/what of the following can be considered most responsible for doping violation?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sportsperson",
    "optionValues": [
      "Supplement",
      "Coach",
      "Sportsperson",
      "Medicines"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0097",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "An athlete’s biological passport is an evidence of his/her:",
    "correctAnswer": "Doping tests collated",
    "optionValues": [
      "Body composition",
      "Clinical markers",
      "Blood profile",
      "Doping tests collated "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0098",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "TUE  in anti-doping is termed as:",
    "correctAnswer": "Therapeutic use exemption",
    "optionValues": [
      "Therapeutic use exemption",
      "Technical use example",
      "Therapeutic use experiments",
      "Therapeutic use of exercise "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0099",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Caffeine is a controlled or a restricted substance as per IOC. The acceptable limit for caffeine in per ml of urine is:",
    "correctAnswer": "12ug/ml",
    "optionValues": [
      "5-7ug/ml",
      "3-4ug/ml",
      "15ug/ml",
      "12ug/ml"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0100",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Which product can result in a two year ban for the athlete - if used in or out of competition in 'shooting'?",
    "correctAnswer": "Beta-blockers",
    "optionValues": [
      "Beta-alanine",
      "Beta-glutamine",
      "Beta-blockers",
      "BCAA"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0101",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "What are the performance benefits of using blood doping in a sport?",
    "correctAnswer": "Increased numbers of RBC and hemoglobin",
    "optionValues": [
      "Increased numbers of RBC and hemoglobin",
      "Decreased cardiac output",
      "Increased blood viscosity",
      "None of the above "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0102",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "What are the physiological reasons that might motivate an elite sportsperson to take steroids?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Aids assimilation of protein",
      "Increased ability to train longer at higher intensities",
      "Increased fat loss",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0103",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Child athletes who take growth hormones are at an increased risk of the following except:",
    "correctAnswer": "Nutrient deficiencies",
    "optionValues": [
      "Gigantism",
      "Insulin resistance",
      "Nutrient deficiencies",
      "Acromegalic syndrome"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0104",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Athletes use amphetamines because their actions mimic the effect of which hormones?",
    "correctAnswer": "Epinephrine and nor-epinephrine",
    "optionValues": [
      "Epinephrine and nor-epinephrine",
      "Growth hormone",
      "Thyroxine",
      "Aldosterone"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0105",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "When an athlete is buying a supplement, what should he check to prevent inadvertent doping?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Composition of the product",
      "Third party certification",
      "Place of manufacture/ import",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0106",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "What are the benefits of using caffeine as an ergogenic aid?",
    "correctAnswer": "Improved alertness and reaction time",
    "optionValues": [
      "Increased Fatigue",
      "Improved alertness and reaction time",
      "Decreased blood glucose",
      "Decreased blood viscosity "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0107",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "High altitude training as an ergogenic aid is most beneficial for which sport?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ultra endurance running",
    "optionValues": [
      "Ultra endurance running",
      "Weightlifting",
      "Sprinting",
      "Speed skating "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0108",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "WADA is the acronym for:",
    "correctAnswer": "World anti-doping agency",
    "optionValues": [
      "World athletics development association",
      "World anti- doping authority",
      "World archery development agency",
      "World anti-doping agency"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0109",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Which of the following can be considered an Anti-doping rule violation for an athlete?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Presence of a prohibited substance",
      "Refusal to report for a test",
      "Use of a prohibited method",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0110",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Mental imagery can be best used as an ergogenic aid to:",
    "correctAnswer": "Familarize with the competition routine or site",
    "optionValues": [
      "Familarize with the competition routine or site",
      "Improved arithmetic ability",
      "Improve strength and performance",
      "None of the above "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0111",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Which protein supplement can be used by a lactose intolerant individual?",
    "correctAnswer": "Whey protein isolate",
    "optionValues": [
      "Whey protein concentrate",
      "Whey protein isolate",
      "Blend of whey protein concentrate and isolate",
      "None of the above- Whey protein cant be used by lactose intolerant"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0112",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Which is the best time to take a whey protein?",
    "correctAnswer": "Post-Exercise and Morning",
    "optionValues": [
      "Post-Exercise and Bedtime",
      "Pre-Exercise and Bedtime",
      "Post-Exercise and Morning",
      "Pre-Exercise and Morning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0113",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Which is the best time to take a casein protein?",
    "correctAnswer": "Pre-Exercise and Bedtime",
    "optionValues": [
      "Post-Exercise and Bedtime",
      "Pre-Exercise and Bedtime",
      "Post-Exercise and Morning",
      "Pre-Exercise and Morning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0114",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Which of the following protein supplements is fastest absorbed?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hydrolysed Whey protein isolate",
    "optionValues": [
      "Hydrolysed Whey protein isolate",
      "Pure Whey protein isolate",
      "Blend of Whey and Casein",
      "Milk protein isolate"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0115",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Which of the following protein supplements is slowest absorbed?",
    "correctAnswer": "Pure Micellar Casein",
    "optionValues": [
      "Blend of Whey and Casein",
      "Pure Milk protein isolate",
      "Calcium and Sodium caseinate",
      "Pure Micellar Casein"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0116",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "If a protein supplement has a Protein:Carb ratio of 1:5, what can it be used for:",
    "correctAnswer": "Weight gain",
    "optionValues": [
      "Weight loss",
      "Maintenance after weight loss",
      "Weight gain",
      "It is a meal replacement that can be used for both weight loss & weight gain"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0117",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "In a BCAA supplement, which ratio of Leucine: Isoleucine: Valine is best to supply energy?",
    "correctAnswer": "2:1:1 ratio",
    "optionValues": [
      "2:1:1 ratio",
      "4:1:1 ratio",
      "8:1:1 ratio",
      "12:1:1 ratio"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0118",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "What is the primary benefit of taking a pure Leucine supplement after exercise?",
    "correctAnswer": "To increase rate of protein synthesis",
    "optionValues": [
      "To increase power",
      "To stimulate increased alertness",
      "To increase vasodilation",
      "To increase rate of protein synthesis"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0119",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "What are the best timings to take Glutamine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Post-Exercise and Bedtime",
    "optionValues": [
      "Post-Exercise and Bedtime",
      "Pre-Exercise and Bedtime",
      "Post-Exercise and Morning",
      "Pre-Exercise and Morning"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0120",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "What are the primary benefits of Glutamine?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Improves muscle recovery",
      "Boosts immunity",
      "Reducing negative effects of cortisol",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0121",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Which of the following help increase vasodilation?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Arginine",
      "Citrulline",
      "Beetroot juice",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0122",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "What is the ideal carbohydrate content in a sports drink?",
    "correctAnswer": "6-8% carbs",
    "optionValues": [
      "1-2% carbs",
      "3-5% carbs",
      "6-8% carbs",
      "9-11% carbs"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0123",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Identify the type of supplement containing: Dextrose- 1.5%, Sodium- 75mmol/L, Chloride- 65 mmol/L, Potassium- 20mmol/L",
    "correctAnswer": "Oral Rehydration Solution",
    "optionValues": [
      "Sports drink",
      "Sports gel",
      "Energy drink",
      "Oral Rehydration Solution"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0124",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Which is the preferred carbohydrate source in a sports drink?",
    "correctAnswer": "A mix of all of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Only Glucose",
      "Only Fructose",
      "Only Maltodextrin",
      "A mix of all of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0125",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "What does a sports gel contain?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Carbohydrates",
      "Electrolytes",
      "Caffeine and/or Vitamins",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0126",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Which of the following can help buffer Lactic acid?",
    "correctAnswer": "Creatine and Beta-alanine",
    "optionValues": [
      "BCAA and Glutamine",
      "Creatine and Beta-alanine",
      "Leucine and Caffeine",
      "Tyrosine and Phenylalanine"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0127",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "What are the advantages of creatine ethyl ester over creatine monohydrate?",
    "correctAnswer": "Better absorption",
    "optionValues": [
      "Better absorption",
      "Glucose is required for its uptake",
      "Lower cost",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0128",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "What should a single dose of creatine monohydrate ideally comprise?",
    "correctAnswer": "3-5gm creatine monohydrate + 50-75gm glucose in water",
    "optionValues": [
      "3-5gm creatine monohydrate in water",
      "6-10gm creatine monohydrate in water",
      "3-5gm creatine monohydrate + 50-75gm glucose in water",
      "6-10gm creatine monohydrate + 50-75gm glucose in water"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0129",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Which of the following would be the preferred choice to have along with creatine?",
    "correctAnswer": "Grape juice",
    "optionValues": [
      "Bananas",
      "Orange juice",
      "Grape juice",
      "Apple juice"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0130",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Which of these supplements would be beneficial to an endurance athlete?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Carnitine",
      "Medium-chain Triglycerides",
      "Coenzyme Q10",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0131",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "4",
    "question": "Which of these supplements would be beneficial to a power athlete?",
    "correctAnswer": "Creatine and Caffeine",
    "optionValues": [
      "Creatine and Caffeine",
      "Carnitine and Beta-alanine",
      "MCTs and Coenzyme Q10",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0132",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "The definition of Cardiorespiratory fitness is",
    "correctAnswer": "The coordinated capacity of the heart, blood vessels, respiratory system and tissues to take in, deliver and use oxygen",
    "optionValues": [
      "The maximal force that a muscle or muscle group can generate in a single effort",
      "The coordinated capacity of the heart, blood vessels, respiratory system and tissues to take in, deliver and use oxygen",
      "The ability to sustain a maximal effort or to continue repeated submaximal contractions",
      "The functional ROM about a joint"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0133",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "From rest to maximal exercise, the systolic blood pressure should ____________ with an increasing workload.",
    "correctAnswer": "Increase",
    "optionValues": [
      "Increase",
      "Decrease",
      "Stay the same",
      "Decrease with isometric or increase with isotonic contractions"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0134",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "The ACSM recommendation for intensity, duration, and frequency of physical activity for apparently healthy individuals includes",
    "correctAnswer": "Intensity of 60% to 90% maximal heart rate, duration of 20-60 min, and frequency of 3 to 5 days a week",
    "optionValues": [
      "Intensity of 60% to 90% maximal heart rate, duration of 20-60 min, and frequency of 3 to 5 days a week",
      "Intensity of 85% to 90% maximal heart rate, duration of 30 minutes, and frequency of 3 days a week",
      "Intensity of 50% to 70% maximal heart rate, duration of 15 to 45 minutes, and frequency of 5 days a week",
      "Intensity of 60% to 90% maximal heart rate reserve, duration of 20 to 60 minutes, and frequency of 7 days a week"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0135",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "The Ventilatory Threshold",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "results from an increase in CO2 due to lactate buffering",
      "usually occurs at 80-85 % VO2max in trained individuals",
      "corresponds to the fall in aerobic energy production from aerobic glycolysis and take over by the anaerobic glycolysis and phosphagen system",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0136",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Which of the below mentioned physiological responses will not occur as a result of regular Cardiovascular training?",
    "correctAnswer": "Resting HR will increase",
    "optionValues": [
      "VO2max will increase",
      "Resting HR will increase",
      "Resting BP will decrease",
      "Exercise HR will decrease"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0137",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Type II muscle fibers",
    "correctAnswer": "Are recruited at a higher percentage of maximum force than Type I fibers",
    "optionValues": [
      "Have a high capacity to generate energy through the electron transport system",
      "Have a high capacity to generate energy from fat",
      "Are recruited at a higher percentage of maximum force than Type I fibers",
      "Have high endurance capabilities"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0138",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Using the original RPE scale (6 to 20), what level of perceived exertion is associated with a Cardio Respiratory Fitness (CRF) training effect?",
    "correctAnswer": "11 to 15",
    "optionValues": [
      "6 to 9",
      "11 to 15",
      "13 to 17",
      "6 to 11"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0139",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Which of the following is/are true with regard to specificity and fitness?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Training effect is limited to the muscle fibers involved in the activity",
      "Muscle fiber adapts specifically to a type of activity",
      "Mitochondria demonstrate greater adaptation with endurance activity",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0140",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "What is the primary physiological benefit to be gained during a cool-down after exercise?",
    "correctAnswer": "Option2 and 3",
    "optionValues": [
      "promotes increase in cardiovascular fitness",
      "prevents venous pooling",
      "facilitates lactate removal",
      "Option2 and 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0141",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Optimal warm up before activity results in which of the following?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Less muscle resistance when the warm-up is performed similarly to the actual activity",
      "Facilitated nerve transmission and motor unit recruitment",
      "Facilitated oxygen delivery and use by the muscle",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0142",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "What happens to the muscle during isometric tension development?",
    "correctAnswer": "No change in the length of the muscle",
    "optionValues": [
      "Shortening of the muscle",
      "Lengthening of the muscle",
      "No change in the length of the muscle",
      "Relaxation of the muscle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0143",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "A female client expresses an interest in joining a recreational crew team. She hires you to train her to withstand the demands of the sport. You design a resistance training program that includes low reps, 4-6 sets of high intensity squats and seated row within a comprehensive  resistance training program. You gradually increase her sets and load/intensity. In addition, you have included sprints and long distance swimming in her overall program plan. Which of the  following training principles have you incorporated?",
    "correctAnswer": "overload, strength and specificity",
    "optionValues": [
      "specificity, reversibility and variation",
      "overload, adaptability and strength",
      "specificity, overload and variation",
      "overload, strength and specificity"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0144",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Muscle hypertrophy refers to",
    "correctAnswer": "an increase in muscle size",
    "optionValues": [
      "immobilization of a muscle",
      "a decrease in muscle size",
      "an increase in muscle size",
      "an increase in number of muscle fibers"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0145",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Neural mechanisms responsible for adaptations in strength and power include all of the following  EXCEPT an increased",
    "correctAnswer": "antagonist muscle coactivation",
    "optionValues": [
      "motor unit recruitment",
      "antagonist muscle coactivation",
      "motor unit firing rate",
      "fast-twitch fiber recruitment"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0146",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "An increase in the number of muscle fibers in a muscle is referred to as:",
    "correctAnswer": "hyperplasia",
    "optionValues": [
      "hyperplasia",
      "atrophy",
      "hypertrophy",
      "hypoplasia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0147",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Which of the following indicates the correct order for a traditional periodization program for resistance training?",
    "correctAnswer": "hypertrophy, strength/power, peaking, recovery",
    "optionValues": [
      "hypertrophy, peaking, strength/power, recovery",
      "strength/power, peaking, recovery, hypertrophy",
      "strength/power, hypertrophy, recovery, peaking",
      "hypertrophy, strength/power, peaking, recovery"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0148",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "What is the equivalent of 2.5 pounds (1.13 kg) of body fat in terms of caloric deficit?",
    "correctAnswer": "8750 kilocalories",
    "optionValues": [
      "5250 kilocalories",
      "7000 kilocalories",
      "8000 kilocalories",
      "8750 kilocalories"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0149",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "The treatment modality RICES includes all of the following EXCEPT",
    "correctAnswer": "Covering",
    "optionValues": [
      "Covering",
      "Ice",
      "Stabilization",
      "Rest"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0150",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Which of the following will not cause an elevation of RHR values?",
    "correctAnswer": "High hemoglobin level",
    "optionValues": [
      "Low stroke volume",
      "Poor oxygen extraction capability",
      "High hemoglobin level",
      "Elevated stress hormones"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0151",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "The difference between the oxygen required to support a given exercise intensity and the actual oxygen consumption at the start of exercise is known as the:",
    "correctAnswer": "oxygen deficit",
    "optionValues": [
      "EPOC",
      "oxygen deficit",
      "lactate threshold",
      "maximum oxygen uptake"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0152",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Which answers are correct? The lactate threshold: i. represents the point at which blood lactate begins to accumulate above resting concentrations during exercise of increasing intensity; ii. represents the point at which lactate production exceeds lactate clearance; iii. occurs at a lower power output after endurance exercise training",
    "correctAnswer": "i and ii",
    "optionValues": [
      "i only",
      "i and ii",
      "i, ii and iii",
      "None of them"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0153",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "During high intensity exercise lasting approximately 2-3 minutes in duration, fatigue is most likely to be caused by:",
    "correctAnswer": "accumulation of metabolic by-products such as lactic acid and H+",
    "optionValues": [
      "depletion of ATP-PCr",
      "accumulation of metabolic by-products such as lactic acid and H+",
      "depletion of glycogen stores",
      "increase in muscle pH"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0154",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Exercise training can lead to a lowering of resting heart rate. This response is known as:",
    "correctAnswer": "bradycardia",
    "optionValues": [
      "subcardia",
      "bradycardia",
      "hypocardia",
      "tachycardia"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0155",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Cardiac output refers to",
    "correctAnswer": "the volume of blood pumped by the heart per minute",
    "optionValues": [
      "the volume of blood pumped by the heart per minute",
      "the proportion of blood pumped out of each ventricle during systole",
      "the volume of blood pumped by the heart per contraction",
      "the product of the ejection fraction and heart rate"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0156",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Stroke volume increases during exercise due to:",
    "correctAnswer": "all of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "greater elastic recoil due to increased filling of the heart",
      "increased ventricular contractility",
      "decreased peripheral resistance",
      "all of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0157",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "When designing training programs, the following should be considered:",
    "correctAnswer": "the principle of progressive overload",
    "optionValues": [
      "the principle of progressive overload",
      "the all-or-none principle",
      "the Fick principle",
      "Boyle's law"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0158",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "For most individuals, stroke volume starts to plateau at approximately _____% of maximal oxygen uptake",
    "correctAnswer": "50%",
    "optionValues": [
      "25%",
      "50%",
      "75%",
      "100%"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0159",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Compared to untrained individuals, trained endurance athletes have",
    "correctAnswer": "higher maximal stroke volumes",
    "optionValues": [
      "higher maximal heart rates",
      "higher resting cardiac outputs",
      "higher resting heart rates",
      "higher maximal stroke volumes"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0160",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Which athlete is the most powerful?",
    "correctAnswer": "athlete A (bench presses 100 kg over 0.6 m in 0.5 s)",
    "optionValues": [
      "athlete A (bench presses 100 kg over 0.6 m in 0.5 s)",
      "athlete B (bench presses 150 kg over 0.6 m in 1.0 s)",
      "athlete C (bench presses 200 kg over 0.6 m in 2.0 s)",
      "athlete D (bench presses 250 kg over 0.6 m in 2.5 s)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0161",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "By inserting rest intervals into anaerobic or aerobic power training programs, athletes",
    "correctAnswer": "can perform a greater volume of work in a session",
    "optionValues": [
      "accumulate more lactate",
      "sustain less muscle damage",
      "build muscle strength faster",
      "can perform a greater volume of work in a session"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0162",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "An eccentric skeletal muscle contraction refers to a contraction where:",
    "correctAnswer": "Force is generated while the muscle is lengthening",
    "optionValues": [
      "Force is generated while the muscle is lengthening",
      "Force is generated while the muscle is shortening",
      "Force is generated but the muscle does not change length",
      "No force is generated by the muscle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0163",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Maximal oxygen uptake (VO2max) is:",
    "correctAnswer": "all of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "the best measure of cardiorespiratory fitness",
      "increases with physical training",
      "declines by ~1% per year in inactive people after the age of 25-30",
      "all of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0164",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "At sea level, minute ventilation increases during exercise primarily to:",
    "correctAnswer": "eliminate carbon dioxide that is produced as a result of increased metabolism",
    "optionValues": [
      "increase loading of oxygen onto hemoglobin to maintain the arterial partial pressure of oxygen",
      "eliminate carbon dioxide that is produced as a result of increased metabolism",
      "lose heat via evaporation",
      "maintain the respiratory pump"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0165",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "The percentage (i.e. relative) increases in strength that can be achieved with resistance training are:",
    "correctAnswer": "similar in males and females",
    "optionValues": [
      "greater in males than females",
      "greater in females than males",
      "similar in males and females",
      "none of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0166",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "In response to aerobic exercise, training heart rate is",
    "correctAnswer": "decreased at a standard submaximal exercise intensity",
    "optionValues": [
      "increased at rest",
      "increased at a standard submaximal exercise intensity",
      "decreased at a standard submaximal exercise intensity",
      "all of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0167",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "One MET is equal to",
    "correctAnswer": "3.5 mL O2/kg body weight /min",
    "optionValues": [
      "350 L O2/kg body weight/week",
      "35 L O2/kg body weight /day",
      "35 mL O2/kg body weight /hour",
      "3.5 mL O2/kg body weight /min"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0168",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Athletes who are successful in endurance type activities are more likely to have a higher proportion of the following muscle fibre type in the skeletal muscles that are the prime movers for the activity in question:",
    "correctAnswer": "Slow-twitch muscle fibres",
    "optionValues": [
      "Fast-glycolytic muscle fibres",
      "Fast oxidative-glycolytic fibres",
      "Slow-twitch muscle fibres",
      "They are more likely to have an even proportion of each"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0169",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "The arteriovenous oxygen difference across a muscle increases with increasing exercise intensity because of",
    "correctAnswer": "increased extraction of oxygen by the muscle",
    "optionValues": [
      "increased delivery of oxygen to the muscle",
      "increased extraction of oxygen by the muscle",
      "decreased delivery of oxygen to the muscle",
      "decreased extraction of oxygen by the muscle"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0170",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Which energy system has the highest power output for ATP production",
    "correctAnswer": "CrP system",
    "optionValues": [
      "Anaerobic glycolysis",
      "Aerobic glycolysis",
      "Beta-oxidation",
      "CrP system"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0171",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "Which of the following adaptations will be apt to increase the work capacity at high altitude?",
    "correctAnswer": "Decreasing workload, increasing duration of exercise",
    "optionValues": [
      "Increasing workload, decreasing duration of exercise",
      "Increasing workload, increasing duration off exercise",
      "Decreasing workload, increasing duration of exercise",
      "Decreasing workload, decreasing duration of exercise"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0172",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "5",
    "question": "When doing a push-up on the floor, the motion at the elbow joint during the down phase is called  ________ and the type of muscle action is called ________.",
    "correctAnswer": "flexion, eccentric",
    "optionValues": [
      "extension, eccentric",
      "flexion, eccentric",
      "flexion, concentric",
      "extension, concentric"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0173",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "Which statement is true regarding informed consent?",
    "correctAnswer": "It should be obtained before an exercise test and before participation in a supervised exercise program",
    "optionValues": [
      "It should be obtained before an exercise test and before participation in a supervised exercise program",
      "It should be obtained before an exercise test but is not needed prior to a supervised exercise program",
      "It should be sent to the potential exercise participant, and the signed form should be mailed to the exercise program director one week prior to program participation.",
      "It should include an explanation of medications the participant should take to reduce muscle soreness."
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0174",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "Barring complications, a submaximal treadmill exercise test is often terminated when the client obtains a predetermined HR endpoint of what percentage of age predicted maximal HR?",
    "correctAnswer": "85",
    "optionValues": [
      "55",
      "65",
      "75",
      "85"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0175",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "Which of the following represents a rank order of the most accurate to the least accurate technique for determining body composition?",
    "correctAnswer": "hydrostatic, skinfold, anthropometric, bioelectrical impedance, infrared interactance",
    "optionValues": [
      "hydrostatic, skinfold, anthropometric, bioelectrical impedance, infrared interactance",
      "hydrostatic, anthropometric, skinfold, infrared interactance, bioelectrical impedance",
      "infrared interactance, hydrostatic, skinfold, anthropometric, bioelectrical impedance",
      "bioelectrical impedance, skinfold, hydrostatic, anthropometric, , infrared interactance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0176",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "As an exercise professional, what should you direct a low-risk male, interested in beginning a low-to-moderate intensity exercise program, to do first?",
    "correctAnswer": "take the PAR-Q +",
    "optionValues": [
      "receive a physician’s clearance",
      "contact a cardiologist to take a Graded Exercise Test",
      "take the PAR-Q +",
      "take the Cooper Walk/Run test"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0177",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "Of the following, which is not an absolute contraindication to exercise testing?",
    "correctAnswer": "uncontrolled metabolic disease",
    "optionValues": [
      "acute infection",
      "uncontrolled metabolic disease",
      "uncontrolled atrial arrhythmia",
      "unstable angina"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0178",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "For how many hours preceding physical fitness testing should the participant be instructed to avoid any food intake",
    "correctAnswer": "Four",
    "optionValues": [
      "One",
      "Twelve",
      "Four",
      "Eight"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0179",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "What is considered the gold standard for determining body composition?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hydrostatic Weighing",
    "optionValues": [
      "Bioelectrical Impedance Analysis",
      "Hydrostatic Weighing",
      "Skinfold measurements",
      "Body mass index"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0180",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "What is considered the gold standard for determining VO2max?",
    "correctAnswer": "Graded Exercise Test using Douglas Bag method",
    "optionValues": [
      "Cooper Walk/Run test",
      "Graded Exercise Test using Douglas Bag method",
      "Queens College Step Test",
      "YMCA Submaximal Cycle ergometry test"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0181",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "What is the duration of each stage in a Bruce Protocol (the most commonly used protocol for VO2max testing?",
    "correctAnswer": "None of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "2 min",
      "5 min",
      "4 min",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0182",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "What minimal baseline measures should be obtained prior to the start of an exercise test for a low-risk individual?",
    "correctAnswer": "Resting HR & Resting BP",
    "optionValues": [
      "Resting HR",
      "Resting BP",
      "Resting ECG",
      "Resting HR & Resting BP"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0183",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "Which of the BP responses would represent a general indication to discontinue a Graded Exercise Test in an apparently healthy adult?",
    "correctAnswer": "SBP drops 20 mmHg with an increase in exercise intensity",
    "optionValues": [
      "SBP drops 20 mmHg with an increase in exercise intensity",
      "SBP rises to 200 mm Hg",
      "DBP fails to increase with increase in exercise intensity",
      "Both Option1 and 3"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0184",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "General indications for discontinuing a Graded Exercise Test in low risk adults would include all but which of the following?",
    "correctAnswer": "Subject’s HR fails to increase with an increase in exercise intensity",
    "optionValues": [
      "Subject asks to stop the test",
      "Subject’s HR increases to 170 beats per minute",
      "Subject shows manifestations of severe fatigue",
      "Subject’s HR fails to increase with an increase in exercise intensity"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0185",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "A person having a BMI of 25.3 would be indicative of being",
    "correctAnswer": "Overweight",
    "optionValues": [
      "Underweight",
      "Normal Weight",
      "Overweight",
      "Obese"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0186",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "As per the latest AHA guidelines, the defining threshold value for Hypertension is",
    "correctAnswer": "≥ 130/80",
    "optionValues": [
      "≥ 130/80",
      "≥ 120/80",
      "≥ 140/90",
      "≥ 160/100"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0187",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "Reasons for fitness testing of the older adult include",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Evaluation of progress",
      "Exercise prescription",
      "Motivation",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0188",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "A measure of muscular endurance is",
    "correctAnswer": "Number of push ups till exhaustion",
    "optionValues": [
      "One-repitition maximum",
      "Three-repitition maximum",
      "Number of push ups till exhaustion",
      "Treadmill testing"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0189",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "Of the following, which is not an objective of a CR fitness assessment in a low-risk individual",
    "correctAnswer": "To identify CV disease",
    "optionValues": [
      "Provide bases for the development of an exercise prescription",
      "To motivate one to begin an exercise program",
      "To identify CV disease",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0190",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "Which of the following best describes the appropriate abdominal skinfold site?",
    "correctAnswer": "Vertical fold taken 2 cms to the right of the umbilicus",
    "optionValues": [
      "Horizontal fold taken 2 cms to the left of the umbilicus",
      "Vertical fold taken 2 cms to the right of the umbilicus",
      "Horizontal fold taken 2 inches to the left of the umbilicus",
      "Vertical fold taken 2 inches to the right of the umbilicus"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0191",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "Relative proportions of fat and fat-free tissue can be assessed and reported as",
    "correctAnswer": "Body composition",
    "optionValues": [
      "Percentage body fat",
      "Body composition",
      "Hydrodensitometry",
      "Near-infrared interactance"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0192",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "6",
    "question": "What is the appropriate sequence for fitness testing?",
    "correctAnswer": "Body composition, cardiorespiratory endurance, muscular fitness, flexibility",
    "optionValues": [
      "Flexibility, cardiorespiratory endurance, muscular fitness, body composition",
      "Cardiorespiratory endurance, flexibility, muscular fitness, body composition",
      "Body composition, cardiorespiratory endurance, muscular fitness, flexibility",
      "Body composition, flexibility, cardiorespiratory endurance, muscular fitness"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0193",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "7",
    "question": "Why does Motivation play an important role in study of sports nutrition?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Motivation influences desire and determination to follow dietary plan.",
      "Motivation influences the ability to initiate and persist on given dietary plan .",
      "Motivation helps face fatigue, boredom, pain and desire to go beyond comfort.",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0194",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "7",
    "question": "Which of the following characteristics has regularly been implicated in the etiology of eating disorders?",
    "correctAnswer": "Perfectionism",
    "optionValues": [
      "Perfectionism",
      "Narcissism",
      "Extroversion",
      "Introversion"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0195",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "7",
    "question": "Which of the following affects performance of athletes?",
    "correctAnswer": "Both A and B are true",
    "optionValues": [
      "Dehydration impairs cognitive functions, influences reaction time, motor task performance and mood states",
      "Over Hydration causes dizziness, nausea, state of confusion, vomiting, swelling of hands and legs.",
      "Neither A nor B is true",
      "Both A and B are true "
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0196",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "7",
    "question": "Food can influence peak performance of players through:",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "Improved body image",
      "Improved health",
      "Increase in energy levels and alertness",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0197",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "7",
    "question": "Fatigue and confidence can be influenced by foods high in:",
    "correctAnswer": "Carbohydrates and Proteins",
    "optionValues": [
      "Carbohydrates and Proteins",
      "Fats and Fibers",
      "Proteins and fats",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0198",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "7",
    "question": "Which of the following needs to be avoided for anxious athletes before or during competition?",
    "correctAnswer": "Foods high in sugar",
    "optionValues": [
      "Foods high in sugar",
      "Foods high in complex carbs",
      "Foods high in protein",
      "Foods high in fats"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0199",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "7",
    "question": "Does Sports Psychology have a role in performance?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mental state and emotions affect performance",
    "optionValues": [
      "Motor Coordination is related to the body, and not the mind.",
      "Efficient Practice leads to excellence in performance, where mind does not play much role.",
      "Mental state and emotions affect performance",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0200",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "7",
    "question": "Behaviours related to nutrition can be modified by:",
    "correctAnswer": "Educational programs and maintaining food mood diary",
    "optionValues": [
      "Putting stringent limits to calorie intake",
      "Keeping a close watch on calorie expenditure",
      "Educational programs and maintaining food mood diary",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0201",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "7",
    "question": "Mental technique of Goal setting can be a determinant in sports success because:",
    "correctAnswer": "Goals give direction and purpose",
    "optionValues": [
      "Goals increase anxiety",
      "Goals increase pressure to perform",
      "Goals reduce confidence",
      "Goals give direction and purpose"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0202",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "7",
    "question": "Which one of the following is a diagnostic criterion for aneroxia nervosa ?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "A refusal to maintain a minimal body weight",
      "A pathological fear of gaining weight",
      "A distorted body image in which even when clearly emaciated, sufferers continue to insist they are overweight",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0203",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "7",
    "question": "Players with bulimia have a perceived lack of control over their eating behaviour and often report which of the following?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "optionValues": [
      "High level of self disgust",
      "Low self esteem",
      "High levels of depression",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0204",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "7",
    "question": "Mindfulness can be used by nutritionists in sports scenarios by:",
    "correctAnswer": "Both B and C",
    "optionValues": [
      "Eating slowly with distractions",
      "Helping players to reach state of full attention to experiences, cravings and physical cues when eating",
      "Engaging senses by noticing colours, smells, sounds, textures and flavours",
      "Both B and C"
    ]
  },
  {
    "id": "a0205",
    "type": "radio",
    "category": "7",
    "question": "Eating disorders can influence an athlete's performance by affecting:",
    "correctAnswer": "Body image and self esteem",
    "optionValues": [
      "Motivation to play",
      "Distraction and inability to concentrate on task relevant cues",
      "Body image and self esteem",
      "All of the above"
    ]
  }
]